<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Infra DX Blog</title>
  
  <link href="/infra-dx-blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-09T23:30:50.487Z</updated>
  <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Infra DX Crew</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>6. See prophecy attached</title>
    <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/06/09/6-See-prophecy-attached/"/>
    <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/06/09/6-See-prophecy-attached/</id>
    <published>2017-06-09T15:54:36.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-09T23:30:50.487Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the <strong>Infra DX Crew</strong>.<br>It’ll contain technical musings, <something else=""> and probably a few memes.</something></p>
<h4 id="TLDR"><a href="#TLDR" class="headerlink" title="TLDR"></a>TLDR</h4><p>The scoping prophets have laid pen on scroll…</p>
<ul>
<li>Marketing site to be getting another make over!</li>
<li>How will we give users a faster (=== better!) experience</li>
<li>A more fitting development process</li>
</ul>
<p>And as for already ongoing things…</p>
<ul>
<li>Second marketing site finally deprecated!!</li>
<li>PaaS progress update</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="prophecy-pdf"><a href="#prophecy-pdf" class="headerlink" title="prophecy.pdf"></a>prophecy.pdf</h2><p><img src="./prophecypdf-l.png" alt=""></p>
<center><i><em>From left to right: the Infra-Dx interpretation and the original transcript itself.</em></i></center>


<h2 id="What-we-worked-on"><a href="#What-we-worked-on" class="headerlink" title="What we worked on"></a>What we worked on</h2><h4 id="Marketing-site-now-singular"><a href="#Marketing-site-now-singular" class="headerlink" title="Marketing site (now singular!)"></a>Marketing site (now singular!)</h4><p>After a long-running effort of migrating page by page, all of the index, careers, about, customers, POPSUGAR case study, The Economist case study pages are now living under the Git repo that we intend to use going forward, kalohq/eros!</p>
<p>The background here is that we wanted to quickly release a new marketing site some time ago which would be a significant overhaul of the previous one, and the agency we hired created a completely new repo, with completely different technologies which were incompatible with our existing CI or website assets.</p>
<p>This meant we had website pages scattered across both repos, duplicate assets, two different CI processes, as well as Nginx proxy logic that could handle routing between two different sites… which we have not been proud of!</p>
<p>The work to untangle this mess has been exclusively drive and pushed by Alex Pate and a huge shout out to him, as we’ll now be able to move a lot faster and be able to optimise our site’s speed and infrastructure. <img class="github-emoji" title=":clap:" alt=":clap:" src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f44f.png?v7" height="20" width="20"></p>
<h4 id="New-case-study"><a href="#New-case-study" class="headerlink" title="New case study"></a>New case study</h4><p>There’s now a new case study on our site for <a href="https://rootsrated.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">RootsRated</a>! You can see it <a href="https://kalohq.com/customers/roots-rated" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p><img src="./roots.png" alt=""></p>
<center><i><em>Sneak view… so hipster!</em></i></center>

<h4 id="UI-styling-abstractions"><a href="#UI-styling-abstractions" class="headerlink" title="UI styling abstractions"></a>UI styling abstractions</h4><p>Continued migrating components into the <a href="https://github.com/kalohq/ui" target="_blank" rel="external">UI library</a>, this week having moved the Checkbox and Radio!</p>
<h4 id="Rebrand"><a href="#Rebrand" class="headerlink" title="Rebrand"></a>Rebrand</h4><p>We can actually start to forget about the rebrand pretty soon.</p>
<p>Our core infrastructure that was still using this mysterious word <code>lystable</code> has been updated this sprint and this includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>LWS files service, so all our shareable file links will now use a rebranded bucket name and</li>
<li>Docker Hub</li>
</ul>
<p>As a sidenote, if you want to see what a Docker Hub 404 page looks like, just type in a random collection of characters: <a href="https://hub.docker.com/u/lystable/" target="_blank" rel="external">https://hub.docker.com/u/lystable/</a>. Ours is not that bad either actually: <a href="https://kalohq.com/lystable" target="_blank" rel="external">https://kalohq.com/lystable</a>. Oh yeah, that Kalo 404 page also got released this sprint. <img class="github-emoji" title=":tada:" alt=":tada:" src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f389.png?v7" height="20" width="20"></p>
<h3 id="PaaS-progress"><a href="#PaaS-progress" class="headerlink" title="PaaS progress"></a>PaaS progress</h3><p>PaaS here, PaaS there… what does this thing even look like anyway?</p>
<p>As this post is public we can’t add the login credentials here, but if you visit the <a href="https://internal-marathon-monitoring.lystable.ink/ui/#/" target="_blank" rel="external">dashboard UI</a> then you can get the credentials from any of Chris, Graeme or Alex Muscar.</p>
<h4 id="Remember-that-CI-end-game-we’re-trying-to-get-to-again"><a href="#Remember-that-CI-end-game-we’re-trying-to-get-to-again" class="headerlink" title="Remember that CI end-game we’re trying to get to again?"></a>Remember that CI end-game we’re trying to get to again?</h4><p>You can refresh your memory by checking the lightning talk slides <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10VvntvUbn5UA9grz4fNabbN5MHsyLDernc-8FkRCY84/edit" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<h4 id="What-did-we-release"><a href="#What-did-we-release" class="headerlink" title="What did we release"></a>What did we release</h4><p>We’ve made progress this past sprint, as we’ve both:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>migrated the application configuration to the LWS repo</p>
</li>
<li><p>deployed the Nameko workers on staging, having stopped the Salt deployment in that environment altogether</p>
</li>
<li><p>integrated the PaaS with our existing service discovery platform (<a href="https://www.consul.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hashicorp’s Consul</a>), which means that we, completely seamlessly, kept all the benefits of <a href="https://www.consul.io/docs/agent/dns.html" target="_blank" rel="external">DNS-based service discovery</a> and service alerting in <a href="https://internal-service-monitoring.lystable.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Grafana</a>. We used Cisco’s open-source project <a href="https://github.com/mantl/mesos-consul" target="_blank" rel="external">mesos-consul</a> to achieve this integration, and guess what: it’s running on the PaaS also :)</p>
</li>
<li><p>updated the re-configuration of LWS and Nameko <a href="https://github.com/kalohq/infrastructure/blob/develop/runbooks/update-lws-config.md" target="_blank" rel="external">runbook</a> to reflect the new way to update application configuration</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>You got that right.. now don’t get too drunk with power!</p>
<p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/BTkWBGZLEcq8E/giphy.gif" alt="wow"></p>
<h4 id="What-more-do-we-need-to-go-live"><a href="#What-more-do-we-need-to-go-live" class="headerlink" title="What more do we need to go live"></a>What more do we need to go live</h4><p>We’ve still only got the PaaS on staging and not on production. The reason for this is we are missing just a bit more tooling. But not too much:</p>
<ul>
<li>expose Docker console logs via the PaaS UI</li>
<li>mount Docker container logs on the PaaS VMs</li>
<li>pick what HW profiles we’re going to use in production going forward</li>
<li>then it’s all the production-readiness boilerplate around external disk volumes, clustering, runbooks on how to manage services, etc… donkey work really</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="./donkey.png" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="Release-Process-Makeover"><a href="#Release-Process-Makeover" class="headerlink" title="Release Process Makeover"></a>Release Process Makeover</h3><h4 id="Motivation"><a href="#Motivation" class="headerlink" title="Motivation"></a>Motivation</h4><p>Driven by the drastic speedup in release times (TTP) that we want (see our <a href="okr post">OKR crew post</a>), and the pace at which we wish to evolve our product, we feel forced to reconsider whether our current release process is a best fit.</p>
<p>Our thoughts are that it’s far from the process we’d like to have, and one of our driving principles is that when development finishes and before the feature has been merged, so should integration testing, user testing and performance testing have also finished. As a result, we’re driven to not just reduce the gap between merging a feature branch and deploying that to production, but to completely remove it.</p>
<p>Obviously this will not be a magical new world where user, performance and integration testing suddenly are part of the CI, which we could definitely work towards, but what we do want to have is the tools to support this in the same way as now, except with less Git and Github faffing about.</p>
<p>A bit more extensive review of current whereabouts and desired process, as well as healthy debate can be found in this <a href="https://gist.github.com/yannispanousis/da5872d22fd64596480ad9bfeff4c3e9" target="_blank" rel="external">gist</a>. Do read through!</p>
<h4 id="Getting-there"><a href="#Getting-there" class="headerlink" title="Getting there"></a>Getting there</h4><p>The work to get us to this new world will involve:</p>
<ul>
<li>ensuring a smooth management of remote deploy environments</li>
<li>allowing remote deploy environments to easily import production-like data</li>
<li>migrating all the Dennis logic around preparing and creating release artifacts into the master branch CI build (incrementing version numbers, adding change logs etc.)</li>
<li>allowing us to optionally utilise the staging environment before releasing, placing a lock on it</li>
<li>scrapping the develop branch</li>
</ul>
<p>We can say with confidence that the path to that simpler world can be worked on incrementally, to the point where we don’t consider the final step of removing <code>develop</code> such a biggie.</p>
<h4 id="Remote-Deploys"><a href="#Remote-Deploys" class="headerlink" title="Remote Deploys"></a>Remote Deploys</h4><p>Remote deployments will be getting more and more love, to the point where we feel very comfortable upgrading components to latest versions, switching out individual components, clearing data and so on.</p>
<p>All of this will be to support early user, integration and performance testing, which is what we consider the ways of gaining the confidence we need to release directly to production.</p>
<p><strong>This sprint</strong> we took a very small first step which is to allow the Github PR and <code>review</code> label to be lazily discovered at the time that the Circle build reaches the point of doing a remote deploy, to check if it should do it or not. This means those changes you used to push without initially having a PR, will now trigger a remote deploy without needing a second push… woot!</p>
<p><img src="./remote-deploy.png" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="What’s-up-next"><a href="#What’s-up-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s up next?"></a>What’s up next?</h2><p>What’s the plan, batman?</p>
<h4 id="Marketing-site-makeover…-again"><a href="#Marketing-site-makeover…-again" class="headerlink" title="Marketing site makeover… again!"></a>Marketing site makeover… again!</h4><p>What with the rebrand, the self team onboarding and new case studies, our product shopfront is ever-changing!</p>
<p>This sprint the new designs will be getting full focus, and if you’re impatient, hit the <a href="https://kalohq.ink" target="_blank" rel="external">staging link</a> or check the <a href="sprint board">sprint board</a> now and then to see how it’s going!</p>
<p><img class="github-emoji" title=":nail_care:" alt=":nail_care:" src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f485.png?v7" height="20" width="20"></p>
<h4 id="Faster-i-e-better-user-experience"><a href="#Faster-i-e-better-user-experience" class="headerlink" title="Faster (i.e. better!) user experience"></a>Faster (i.e. better!) user experience</h4><p>Chris is back!</p>
<p>After catching up with all the emails, he’s gonna be pushing the agenda on performance improvements, which means scoping work across cohorts and rolling out bundle optimisations for faster application load times… it’s gonna be a huge team effort from all of us for our users!</p>
<p><img class="github-emoji" title=":racing_car:" alt=":racing_car:" src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f3ce.png?v7" height="20" width="20"></p>
<h4 id="More-holidays"><a href="#More-holidays" class="headerlink" title="More holidays"></a>More holidays</h4><p>Yes, yes Yannis is on holiday again… for the whole of next week… but look at all that stuff we delivered! <img class="github-emoji" title=":beach_umbrella:" alt=":beach_umbrella:" src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f3d6.png?v7" height="20" width="20"></p>
<h2 id="Release-watch"><a href="#Release-watch" class="headerlink" title="Release watch"></a>Release watch</h2><h4 id="Backend"><a href="#Backend" class="headerlink" title="Backend"></a>Backend</h4><p>Flying for the most part, we had <strong>4 out of 5 minor releases under 3 hours</strong> but 1 outlier taking 24 hours.</p>
<p>Take-aways here:</p>
<ul>
<li>more user testing before staging</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Frontend"><a href="#Frontend" class="headerlink" title="Frontend"></a>Frontend</h4><p>Believe it or not, frontend releases have been even faster than that, we’re rolling them out at an average of 75 minutes per release! A big shout out to everyone on the frontend!</p>
<p><img class="github-emoji" title=":clap:" alt=":clap:" src="https://assets-cdn.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f44f.png?v7" height="20" width="20"></p>
<h2 id="Au-revoir"><a href="#Au-revoir" class="headerlink" title="Au revoir!"></a>Au revoir!</h2><p><img src="./aurevoir.png" alt=""></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the &lt;strong&gt;Infra DX Crew&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;It’ll cont
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>5. Man down</title>
    <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/31/5-man-down/"/>
    <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/31/5-man-down/</id>
    <published>2017-05-31T13:46:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-09T15:08:29.208Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the <strong>Infra DX Crew</strong>.<br>It’ll contain technical musings, <something else=""> and probably a few memes.</something></p>
<h4 id="TLDR"><a href="#TLDR" class="headerlink" title="TLDR"></a>TLDR</h4><ul>
<li>Kicked off lots of things: data loading, pagination UX, and performance.</li>
<li>Code splitting (mostly) there 🎉</li>
<li>Refined <a href="https://gist.github.com/chrisui/9d474b9a23e9ab9cbfc21445f98c2785" target="_blank" rel="external">frontend cohort process</a></li>
<li>Category update improvements</li>
<li>A (slightly) new landing page</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="Intro"><a href="#Intro" class="headerlink" title="Intro"></a>Intro</h2><p>After a pretty intense rebrand focused sprint, things are <em>mostly</em> back to normal. Although for the past and upcoming sprints, the crew has mostly been one man down:</p>
<ul>
<li>Yannis was away for most of the previous sprint</li>
<li>Chris is away for most of the upcoming sprint</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="What-we-worked-on"><a href="#What-we-worked-on" class="headerlink" title="What we worked on"></a>What we worked on</h2><p>Where has our focus been?</p>
<h4 id="Data-loading-UX"><a href="#Data-loading-UX" class="headerlink" title="Data loading UX"></a>Data loading UX</h4><p>Chris kicked off discussions with the product team around data loading and the best UX practices surrounding this.</p>
<p>He’s also done some cool work on building out some skeleton components, that can be used to reduce the perceived load time that a user experiences.</p>
<p><img src="./skeleton-kit.png" alt="Skeleton Loading Kit"></p>
<h4 id="Code-splitting"><a href="#Code-splitting" class="headerlink" title="Code splitting"></a>Code splitting</h4><p>Chris has powered on with the performance theme, looking at how our frontend bundles can be split up to only load code when it’s required.</p>
<h4 id="Refined-f-e-cohort-process"><a href="#Refined-f-e-cohort-process" class="headerlink" title="Refined f/e cohort process"></a>Refined f/e cohort process</h4><p>As part of the ongoing push to document all the things, Chris has put together some documentation on the processes of the Frontend Cohort, which you can check out <strong><a href="https://gist.github.com/chrisui/9d474b9a23e9ab9cbfc21445f98c2785" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>!</strong></p>
<h4 id="New-landing-page-header"><a href="#New-landing-page-header" class="headerlink" title="New landing page header"></a>New landing page header</h4><p>We’ve shipped the new header of our landing page, designed by Pete and featuring one of our customers.</p>
<p><img src="./eros-header.jpg" alt="Eros Header"></p>
<h4 id="Slow-category-updates"><a href="#Slow-category-updates" class="headerlink" title="Slow category updates"></a>Slow category updates</h4><p>Slow category update improvements have been reviewed and are ready, but we’ll be preceding them with a couple days of monitoring to get a fact-based measurement for how much better we’ve made it for the user, as well as to be better aware of Elasticsearch indexing issues in the future.</p>
<h2 id="What’s-up-next"><a href="#What’s-up-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s up next?"></a>What’s up next?</h2><h4 id="Marketing-site-updates"><a href="#Marketing-site-updates" class="headerlink" title="Marketing site updates"></a>Marketing site updates</h4><p>I (Alex) will continue on migrating pages from the old marketing site in to our shiny new repo. We’re about 75% of the way to having one repo, and on track to migrate everything by the end of the quarter.</p>
<h4 id="PasS-Platform-as-a-Service"><a href="#PasS-Platform-as-a-Service" class="headerlink" title="PasS (Platform as a Service)"></a>PasS (Platform as a Service)</h4><p>Yannis will start working on getting the Nameko workers deploying in the new way, and this infra should be deployed on staging, without the changes yet being reflected in the LWS repo, so we can ensure stability. Check out <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-63" target="_blank" rel="external">this ticket</a> for more context.</p>
<p>Also PaaS related, Yannis has started on integrating it with Consul to achieve service discovery, which will result in DNS-based service discovery and alerting as a result, out of the box 🎁.</p>
<h4 id="Category-update-improvements"><a href="#Category-update-improvements" class="headerlink" title="Category update improvements"></a>Category update improvements</h4><p>Yannis will be releasing the updates to address the slow category updates (see above) this sprint.</p>
<h2 id="Release-Watch"><a href="#Release-Watch" class="headerlink" title="Release Watch"></a>Release Watch</h2><blockquote>
<p>This is a recurring section retrospecting any releases which didn’t seem to go as smoothly as we would’ve liked.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="Backend"><a href="#Backend" class="headerlink" title="Backend"></a>Backend</h4><ul>
<li>Total number of releases: 4</li>
<li>Average release time: 120 minutes</li>
<li>Maximum release time: 180 minutes</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Frontend"><a href="#Frontend" class="headerlink" title="Frontend"></a>Frontend</h4><ul>
<li>Total number of releases: 1</li>
<li>Average release time: 180 minutes</li>
<li>Maximum release time: 180 minutes</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See ya!<br>✌️ AP</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the &lt;strong&gt;Infra DX Crew&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;It’ll cont
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>4. Three wise men</title>
    <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/24/4-Three-wise-men/"/>
    <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/24/4-Three-wise-men/</id>
    <published>2017-05-24T21:22:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-09T15:08:29.208Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the <strong>Infra DX Crew</strong>.<br>It’ll contain technical musings, <something else=""> and probably a few memes.</something></p>
<h4 id="TLDR"><a href="#TLDR" class="headerlink" title="TLDR"></a>TLDR</h4><ul>
<li>We have a new crew member! Welcome <strong>Alex Pate</strong>!</li>
<li>We’re taking a week off! (Not quite so bluntly but we do have a few holidays over this sprint and the next)</li>
<li>We rebranded! Huge effort from Yannis and AP on planning and executing the engineering side.</li>
<li>There’s an awesome new “Skeleton UI Kit” coming</li>
<li>Work is ticking along nicely on the performance focus<ul>
<li>Core bundles are at &gt;30% reduction</li>
<li>Done an initial investigation into data loading (work being scoped)</li>
<li>Kicking off scoping of work around ux patterns</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Not too much in <strong>Release Watch</strong> this week. Most releases take an hour from prep to deploy.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="“What-even-is-Myrrh-”"><a href="#“What-even-is-Myrrh-”" class="headerlink" title="“What even is Myrrh?”"></a><em>“What even is Myrrh?”</em></h2><p>We have added a seriously wise man to the crew in AP. With our focus being on ensuring engineers have what they need to deliver a good platform while also keeping that platform working as smooth as possible we saw a definite alignment with Alex’s goals. Alex focus is, with a design mindset, to bring stability and consistency to how we engineer UI’s at Lystable. At least that’s what it is until he tells me that’s wrong after he reads this. Anyhow!</p>
<p>Get on with it, Chris.</p>
<h2 id="What-we-worked-on"><a href="#What-we-worked-on" class="headerlink" title="What we worked on"></a>What we worked on</h2><p>Where has our focus been?</p>
<h4 id="Smoothest-Rebrand-EVER"><a href="#Smoothest-Rebrand-EVER" class="headerlink" title="Smoothest Rebrand EVER"></a>Smoothest Rebrand EVER</h4><p>Thanks to some awesome planning and work by Yannis, AP and the rest of the rebrand team this execution on Monday went off and was completed within under 2 hours.</p>
<p><br><br><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/AP94i0chEPXSU/giphy.gif" alt="smooooth"></p>
<p><center>Smoother than P Diddy</center><br><br></p>
<p>It’s worth noting that there is still lots of internal infra that will be renamed over coming weeks so keep your eye out for “Lystable”, whatever <em>that</em> is.</p>
<h4 id="Performance-investigation"><a href="#Performance-investigation" class="headerlink" title="Performance investigation"></a>Performance investigation</h4><p>We’ve spent some time investigating the loading performance of certain areas of our application and by breaking down events into a high level timeline we’ve been able to target some improvements to make.</p>
<p>See the initial glimpse <a href="https://github.com/kalohq/frontend/blob/10015a8ca2d3a43ca5a40fb6b60ff4fc18a16377/docs/research/170516-data-fetching-performance.md" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></p>
<p>Here’s an example timeline we came up with:</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">-----&gt; | Fetch unrelated queries for hidden ui</div><div class="line">-----&gt; | Fetch projects list</div><div class="line">       | ---&gt; | void (cpu churn?)</div><div class="line">              | -----&gt; | Fetch related freelancers</div><div class="line">              | -----&gt; | Fetch related users</div><div class="line">                | ---&gt; | void (cpu churn?)</div><div class="line">                       | -----&gt; | Fetch freelancer &amp; user image files</div><div class="line">                       | -----&gt; | Fetch freelancer skills (unused)</div><div class="line">                       | -----&gt; | Fetch freelancer profiles (unused)</div><div class="line">                                | ---&gt; | void (cpu churn?) before rendering results</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>We’ll be taking this and discussing across cohorts what actions we can take to fix the issues here. We’ll aim to scope up this work so we can prioritise it this quarter.</p>
<h4 id="Skeleton-layouts"><a href="#Skeleton-layouts" class="headerlink" title="Skeleton layouts"></a>Skeleton layouts</h4><p>In an effort to make loading of pages less janky we are introducing a design paradigm called “skeleton loading”. This shows rough outlines of the anticipated content layout while it is loading. We can show this while loading assets, data or anything!</p>
<p>You can follow the PR for this ui kit <a href="https://github.com/kalohq/ui/pull/7" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/1042432/26374037/c222cfa4-3ffb-11e7-9589-65a686083db9.png" alt="skeleton ui"></p>
<h2 id="Release-Watch"><a href="#Release-Watch" class="headerlink" title="Release Watch"></a>Release Watch</h2><p>Going to ignore the hotfixes for the rebrand here since they are very special cases. (v0.199.1 f/e, v0.214.1 b/e)</p>
<h4 id="Frontend"><a href="#Frontend" class="headerlink" title="Frontend"></a>Frontend</h4><ul>
<li>1 minor release (70 mins)</li>
<li>2 hotfix releases (1 hour and 5.5 hours)</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Backend"><a href="#Backend" class="headerlink" title="Backend"></a>Backend</h4><ul>
<li>1 minor release (72 mins)</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Takeaways"><a href="#Takeaways" class="headerlink" title="Takeaways"></a>Takeaways</h4><ul>
<li>We’re generally sitting around an hour for releases which which is pretty good but we hope to improve!</li>
<li>Should investigate why a hotfix was sitting around for nearly 6 hours</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="What’s-up-next"><a href="#What’s-up-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s up next?"></a>What’s up next?</h2><p>What’s the plan, batman?</p>
<h5 id="Holiday-Season"><a href="#Holiday-Season" class="headerlink" title="Holiday Season"></a>Holiday Season</h5><p>Yannis is only here one day next week (in the sprint) where he’ll be mostly tidying up final rebrand infra bits and doing a bit of work on slow category updates.</p>
<p>I (Chris) am only here Thursday/Friday and I’m focusing on getting the code splitting work into a “ready to merge and release” state while scoping a ton of work for next month across design, frontend and backend (all focused around performance).</p>
<h5 id="Continued-marketing-migration"><a href="#Continued-marketing-migration" class="headerlink" title="Continued marketing migration"></a>Continued marketing migration</h5><p>AP is continuing to migrate old marketing pages into the new site.</p>
<p>You can see all the planned work for this sprint on our <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/secure/RapidBoard.jspa?rapidView=13" target="_blank" rel="external">jira board</a>!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Thanks for reading!<br>Chris</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the &lt;strong&gt;Infra DX Crew&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;It’ll cont
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>3. To be named</title>
    <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/19/3-to-be-named/"/>
    <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/19/3-to-be-named/</id>
    <published>2017-05-19T11:45:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-09T15:08:29.208Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the <strong>Infra DX Crew</strong>.<br>It’ll contain technical musings, <something else=""> and probably a few memes.</something></p>
<h4 id="TLDR"><a href="#TLDR" class="headerlink" title="TLDR"></a>TLDR</h4><ul>
<li>A new <strong>Release Watch</strong> section on the blog to retrospect releases with hiccups.</li>
<li>Lots of progress on PaaS which Yannis will be giving a run through of on Monday!</li>
<li>Feature flag service <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-77" target="_blank" rel="external">deployed</a>.</li>
<li>Code splitting showing good trends with a ~20% reduction in initial bundle so far.</li>
<li>Documentation: Strategy and specific form documentation delivered.</li>
<li>Netflix functionality officially <em>DEAD</em> on the front-end.</li>
<li>Rebrand! Rebrand! Rebrand!</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="Intro"><a href="#Intro" class="headerlink" title="Intro"></a>Intro</h2><p><img src="./hellokalo.png" alt="hello kalo"></p>
<p>The last sprint certainly had some interesting bumps (and a lot of 🍻) but beyond all that <em>we have a new name</em>! The rebrand is pretty much going to take over a few people’s sprint this week which is a shame, but we’ve put a lot of effort into planning to make sure it doesn’t spiral out of control.</p>
<p><em>This sprint update is coming a little late owing to some illness so we’re already over half way through already!</em></p>
<h2 id="What-we-worked-on"><a href="#What-we-worked-on" class="headerlink" title="What we worked on"></a>What we worked on</h2><p>Where has our focus been?</p>
<h4 id="PaaS"><a href="#PaaS" class="headerlink" title="PaaS"></a>PaaS</h4><p>More work than can fit in an update has been delivered on this front and Yannis will be delivering this in a presentation/demo/slides format soon!</p>
<p>From Yannis himself:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>A brave new world of more control is approaching, and that’s not only for new services…! Stay tuned for the scheduled update on Monday 4.30pm UK time in the London kitchen.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="Documentation"><a href="#Documentation" class="headerlink" title="Documentation"></a>Documentation</h4><ol>
<li>We published our mid-term strategy for documentation. You can read it in the gist <a href="https://gist.github.com/chrisui/552455b3bfd1d56a95e2d93c7a0d05fb" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>!</li>
<li>We delivered documentation all about how we approach forms on the front-end. This covers everything from the theory to the various abstractions we have in place to help build forms in our applications. You can find the entry point to these docs <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/blob/develop/docs/guides/forms.md" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="Code-splitting"><a href="#Code-splitting" class="headerlink" title="Code splitting"></a>Code splitting</h4><p>Some considerable work has gone into updating how we bundle together our applications and deliver them to the user. This is all working towards faster AND more sustainable [at scale] load times.</p>
<p>You can follow along on the <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1883" target="_blank" rel="external">Pull Request</a> though it’s pretty wip atm.</p>
<p>Some highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Using an extracted manifest to leverage browser cache better when only part of the application updates</li>
<li>A specific “vendor” bundle to, again, leverage browser cache when our dependencies aren’t changing</li>
<li>Targeting some duplicated/fat dependencies</li>
<li>Lots more tweaking to be done to minimize initial load of main app bundles.</li>
<li>Further identified/scoped work<ul>
<li>Use prefetching/preloading to speed up load times even further. <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-85" target="_blank" rel="external">INFRA-85</a></li>
<li>Parallelize loading of bundles and data those bundles will require when they can initialise </li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Netflix-GONE"><a href="#Netflix-GONE" class="headerlink" title="Netflix GONE"></a>Netflix GONE</h4><p>We’ve officially removed the last netflix-specific features from the UI.</p>
<p><img src="./killnetflix.png" alt="kill netflix"></p>
<h4 id="Marketing-site-consolidations"><a href="#Marketing-site-consolidations" class="headerlink" title="Marketing site consolidations"></a>Marketing site consolidations</h4><p>With AlexP’s invaluable help in migrating the index page from <code>lystable/lystable</code> to <code>lystable/eros</code> we switched the primary S3 bucket in the Nginx proxy to be <code>lystable/eros</code> and we now only need to migrate the last few pages from <code>lystable/lystable</code> until we can kill it forever!!</p>
<p>Tracked <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-76" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></p>
<h2 id="Release-Watch"><a href="#Release-Watch" class="headerlink" title="Release Watch"></a>Release Watch</h2><blockquote>
<p>This is a recurring section retrospecting any releases which didn’t seem to go as smoothly as we would’ve liked.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="Backend"><a href="#Backend" class="headerlink" title="Backend"></a>Backend</h4><p>Releases this week have been as light as…… a kalo leaf!</p>
<p><img src="https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/236x/fb/c8/e8/fbc8e83dfc69fef4029c0ca69c2c49d2.jpg" alt="kalo leaf"></p>
<ul>
<li>Number of minor releases: 6</li>
<li>Number of hotfix releases: 1</li>
<li>Average release time for backend: 70 minutes</li>
<li>Maximum release time: 90 minutes</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Frontend"><a href="#Frontend" class="headerlink" title="Frontend"></a>Frontend</h4><p>Frontend have been a bit of a mix, with a couple reaching lava speed</p>
<p><img src="http://study.com/cimages/multimages/16/lavaflow.jpg" alt="lava"></p>
<ul>
<li>Number of minor releases: 4</li>
<li>Number of hotfix releases: 0</li>
<li>50% of the releases averaged: 60 minutes</li>
<li>50% of the releases were at: 24 hours</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Takeaways-this-week"><a href="#Takeaways-this-week" class="headerlink" title="Takeaways this week"></a>Takeaways this week</h4><p>Focus on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Early integration testing</li>
<li>Early user testing or imperfect releasing with hotfix release to achieve the ideal design shortly after</li>
<li>More frequent releasing, to avoid needing to identify which feature PR the error was caused by the natural assumption in this case was the error came from the dominant PR which consisted 98% of the code changes, but we were wrong… !</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="Work-for-Infra-DX"><a href="#Work-for-Infra-DX" class="headerlink" title="Work for Infra-DX"></a>Work for Infra-DX</h4><ul>
<li>Giving early emphasis to flakey failures which hopefully Chris’ work on tracking flakey tests will help</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="What’s-up-next"><a href="#What’s-up-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s up next?"></a>What’s up next?</h2><p>What’s the plan, batman?</p>
<h5 id="Rebrand-Rebrand-Rebrand"><a href="#Rebrand-Rebrand-Rebrand" class="headerlink" title="Rebrand! Rebrand! Rebrand!"></a>Rebrand! Rebrand! Rebrand!</h5><p><a href="http://itsalmo.st/#rebrandtime" target="_blank" rel="external">Time is ticking</a>!</p>
<p>We’re doing our best to roll out all the infrastructure we can, in advance of the launch time, to minimise the buttons we have to press at the final moments of “Lystable”, to reduce the moving parts and any potential risks.</p>
<p><strong>Plan of action</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>We’ll be testing all of the infra, platform and marketing changes on staging (kalohq.ink!) on Friday 19th</li>
<li>We’ll rollout the new marketing site to production on new S3 buckets and side by side on the Nginx proxy</li>
<li>Come launch time, which is 1pm on Monday 22nd, we’ll rollout: backend, frontend, Nginx redirects… simples!</li>
</ul>
<p>Tracked <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-64" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<h5 id="More-Performance-Drive"><a href="#More-Performance-Drive" class="headerlink" title="More Performance Drive"></a>More Performance Drive</h5><p>Just a continuation of the ongoing performance focus. The ultimate goal for this sprint is to have a) scalable front-end builds and b) we have identified and scoped work to improve data performance everywhere.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-18" target="_blank" rel="external">Optimise builds</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-73" target="_blank" rel="external">Data performance investigations</a></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="E2E-retries-and-insights"><a href="#E2E-retries-and-insights" class="headerlink" title="E2E retries and insights"></a>E2E retries and insights</h4><p>Browser based e2e tests are always going to have <em>some</em> level of flakiness. They cover your entire stack and are prone to difficult to predict environmental issues. </p>
<p>Often we get into the habit of seeing an e2e failure and “just hitting rebuild”. We want to avoid this and be able to efficiently tackle areas of flakiness to push ourselves to the best possible situation.</p>
<p>For this we have planned two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>Automatically retry failed scenarios. If it fails twice in a row we consider this a <strong>true failure</strong> and if it passes second time we class this as a <strong>flake failure</strong>. The author of these builds will be notified as such.</li>
<li>Track all these failures with our new tracking api. This should help us identify sources of problems as well as give us the best priorities to tackle.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Insert-witty-ending"><a href="#Insert-witty-ending" class="headerlink" title="Insert witty ending"></a>Insert witty ending</h2><p>Way too tired for a full conclusion this week. As always feel free to reach out and chat about anything from above!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Thanks for reading!<br>Chris</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the &lt;strong&gt;Infra DX Crew&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;It’ll cont
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2. And so, man was given purpose</title>
    <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/11/2-man-was-given-purpose/"/>
    <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/11/2-man-was-given-purpose/</id>
    <published>2017-05-11T10:53:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-09T15:33:13.718Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the <strong>Infra DX Crew</strong>.<br>It’ll contain technical musings, <something else=""> and probably a few memes.</something></p>
<h4 id="TLDR"><a href="#TLDR" class="headerlink" title="TLDR"></a>TLDR</h4><ul>
<li>we’ve placed our quarterly targets! (really really far away)</li>
<li>end-to-end failure debugging is given some love</li>
<li>some casual platform house-keeping: wiping of the <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1874" target="_blank" rel="external">email history</a> feature</li>
<li>users need to brace themselves for our speedy app loading (in the works)</li>
<li>a sneak peek of the Platform-as-a-Service on .ink!</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="On-your-mark-steady-go"><a href="#On-your-mark-steady-go" class="headerlink" title="On your mark, steady, go!"></a>On your mark, steady, go!</h2><p>As Sprint 2 (of the blog history) begins, we’ve set our quarterly targets and the race begins!</p>
<p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/xxaQaFFAT1dcY/giphy.gif" alt="wow"></p>
<p>We think we know our targets better than those guys:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Domain</th>
<th>Metric</th>
<th style="text-align:center">Current</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Target</th>
<th>%</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Dev</td>
<td><strong>Time-to-production</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">~30 hours</td>
<td style="text-align:right">3 hours</td>
<td><strong>-90%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dev</td>
<td><strong>CI feedback time (frontend)</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">50 minutes</td>
<td style="text-align:right">15 minutes</td>
<td><strong>-75%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dev</td>
<td><strong>CI feedback time (backend)</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">15 minutes</td>
<td style="text-align:right">10 minutes</td>
<td><strong>-30%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>User</td>
<td><strong>Time to load applications</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">5.7 seconds</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2.3 seconds</td>
<td><strong>-60%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>User</td>
<td><strong>Time to initialise hera app</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">2 seconds</td>
<td style="text-align:right">0.5 seconds</td>
<td><strong>-75%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>User</td>
<td><strong>Time to load fresh projects index</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">2.2 seconds</td>
<td style="text-align:right">0.6 seconds</td>
<td><strong>-75%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>User</td>
<td><strong>Time to load fresh tasks index</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">2 seconds</td>
<td style="text-align:right">0.5 seconds</td>
<td><strong>-75%</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>User</td>
<td><strong>Time to load fresh invoices index</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:center">1.9 seconds</td>
<td style="text-align:right">0.5 seconds</td>
<td><strong>-75%</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I guess it helps to explain a couple of those.</p>
<p><strong>Time-to-production</strong> is calculated from when a release is started (e.g. <code>dennis prepare</code> in our case) until the code is deployed and ready for customers to use. The metric we have taken is targeted at minor releases.</p>
<p><strong>CI feedback time</strong> is the time it takes for the CI to confirm a change is good to merge. Keep in mind: the <strong>failure</strong> notification on Frontend is much better than that, since we don’t wait for CircleCI to finish the build.</p>
<p><strong>Time to load applications</strong> is the time until we can start fetching data to load an individual page… say whaaat?! We’re shocked too, we’ve already got work you can follow below that will tackle this.</p>
<p><strong>Time to initialise / load</strong> refers to data fetching from the API. As with everything, we’re looking to SLASH this and give our users an experience they feel frictioness in and just love coming back to.</p>
<p>It’s most certainly a quarter full of speeding up our product in every way, indicative of how much amazing work we’ve put into it so far.</p>
<h3 id="Will-Q3-targets-have-to-be-full-of-speedups-again"><a href="#Will-Q3-targets-have-to-be-full-of-speedups-again" class="headerlink" title="Will Q3 targets have to be full of speedups again?"></a>Will Q3 targets have to be full of speedups again?</h3><p>You’ll probably be thinking that the product is going to continue to grow, and we agree.</p>
<p>As for the dev domain OKRs, the core principle that will underlie the solutions will be to render our builds horizontally scalable, to the degree where we’re not running into a risk of significant fluctuation in build times. This is also worth considering in line with the microservices architecture, one of the criteria of which is that we don’t have to build and test all our software every time.</p>
<p>App loading and data fetching times will be <a href="https://internal-event-monitoring.lystable.com" target="_blank" rel="external">monitored closely</a> as we add new workflows and we’ll, at least reactively but much quicker than before, be able to know that our users are going through a bad experience. It’s been made <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1787" target="_blank" rel="external">extremely easy</a> to push time metrics on new pages or different parts of the way as the page loads.</p>
<h3 id="Quick-wins-for-front-end-builds-for-users"><a href="#Quick-wins-for-front-end-builds-for-users" class="headerlink" title="Quick wins for front-end builds (for users!)"></a>Quick wins for front-end builds (for users!)</h3><p>Following some helpful advice from webpack maintainers we took a deeper dive. Some interesting finds! We’re holding off on releasing this until we can see the impact on a more distributed bundle (ie. from code splitting).</p>
<p>Track here: <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1866" target="_blank" rel="external">https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1866</a></p>
<h3 id="E2E-JS-Errors"><a href="#E2E-JS-Errors" class="headerlink" title="E2E JS Errors"></a>E2E JS Errors</h3><p>Haven’t you been yearning for these elusive console errors? ‘Till now you had to run on local and log into the VNC session before you saw the console error. Thanks to this extra dump on the CI or at the end of your local run, that is no more :)</p>
<p>Read more: <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1773" target="_blank" rel="external">https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1773</a></p>
<p><img src="./e2ejserrors.png" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="Introduced-prettier-to-front-end"><a href="#Introduced-prettier-to-front-end" class="headerlink" title="Introduced prettier to front-end"></a>Introduced prettier to front-end</h3><p>Allowing us to focus on writing the code and not thinking about the style.</p>
<p>Read more here: <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1683" target="_blank" rel="external">https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1683</a></p>
<p>Will be some follow up to improve the experience of partial adoption over coming sprints!</p>
<h3 id="Are-we-rebranding-in-the-middle-of-this"><a href="#Are-we-rebranding-in-the-middle-of-this" class="headerlink" title="Are we rebranding in the middle of this?"></a>Are we rebranding in the middle of this?</h3><p>Are we? Oh yes, there’s been a bit of <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1GWbkShkMMBHX0FQVOWlnBiIOs2jDLEBgBXe45nAhx6M/edit" target="_blank" rel="external">scoping</a> going on… it’s really as simple as</p>
<p><img src="./stevable.png" alt="wow"></p>
<p>We put aside a 5-pointer ticket to wrap this Bash command up in a script, we should remember to start it with <code>!#/bin/bash</code> or just be explicit about the interpreter we want to use when running it <code>bash &lt;script&gt;</code>. So long as we get the acceptance criteria straight on the ticket we should be fine. We reckon we’ll run this in production on the 22nd of May.</p>
<h3 id="PaaS-Platform-as-a-Service-sneak-peek"><a href="#PaaS-Platform-as-a-Service-sneak-peek" class="headerlink" title="PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) sneak peek"></a>PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) sneak peek</h3><p>The Platform-as-a-Service tool that we’re setting up is motivated largely by the backend cohort’s <a href="https://trello.com/c/l5oUlCku/54-the-move-to-microservices" target="_blank" rel="external">microservices architecture movement</a>, while it has also been known as an eventuality as our platform and customer base grows.</p>
<p>What problem is it solving? Well, to put it simply, as the number of services in production continue to grow there’s a few things that became unscalable:</p>
<ul>
<li>the adjusting of production capacity because a new feature</li>
<li>the rollout of a new service</li>
<li>the re-configuration of a service</li>
<li>the moving of services from one failed VM to another</li>
</ul>
<p>The PaaS gives us a single interface, UI and API, to manage creation, configuration, scaling and deploying of services. Not only that, it means we can have any VM size we prefer, and the scaling of services will be as fast as it is to deploy Docker containers, rather than VMs. :tada: :tada: :tada:</p>
<p>With the current production architecture the only way to scale the platform would be to hire more people, just to manage the moving around of services in production. Other options would be to give 1 service or 1 service stack per VM, and scale those individually. But that would also be 1) slow and, 2) a huge headache because we’d have to create our own conventions for creating a new service, an auto-scaling group in AWS, yada yada yada.</p>
<p>In comes <a href="https://mesosphere.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Mesosphere</a>!</p>
<p>We’ve deployed it on staging with a <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-50" target="_blank" rel="external">really basic configuration</a> but you can see what <a href="https://internal-mesos-monitoring.lystable.ink/#/" target="_blank" rel="external">Mesos</a>, which effectively acts like a distributed operating system, and <a href="https://internal-marathon-monitoring.lystable.ink/ui/#/apps" target="_blank" rel="external">Marathon</a>, your service management interface are looking like.</p>
<p><img src="./hw-resources.png" alt="hola"><img src="./paas.png" alt="hola"></p>
<p>It’s still <strong>very</strong> much in the works and you can <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-31" target="_blank" rel="external">track it here</a>. There’ll be a :zap: talk on this stuff as we get some more parts of it out, no doubt :)</p>
<h2 id="What’s-up-next"><a href="#What’s-up-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s up next?"></a>What’s up next?</h2><ul>
<li>Code splitting (improving performance of loading applications for users and developers alike!)</li>
<li>Data performance investigation (aimed at identifying the steps we need to take to reduce load times for data)</li>
<li>Documentation strategy!</li>
<li>Forms documented! (call to arms for review <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1845" target="_blank" rel="external">https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1845</a>)</li>
<li>Writing up that rebrand.sh script</li>
<li>Getting one of our Nameko workers to deploy through Marathon from CircleCI!</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Ending-with-a-bombshell…"><a href="#Ending-with-a-bombshell…" class="headerlink" title="Ending with a bombshell…"></a>Ending with a bombshell…</h2><p><img src="./rainy-bcn.png" alt=""></p>
<center><i><em>Not everyday is it sunny in sunny Barcelona!</em></i></center>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the &lt;strong&gt;Infra DX Crew&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;It’ll cont
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>1. In the beginning</title>
    <link href="https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/03/1-In-the-beginning/"/>
    <id>https://kalohq.github.io/infra-dx-blog/2017/05/03/1-In-the-beginning/</id>
    <published>2017-05-03T19:01:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-05-11T13:50:37.387Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the <strong>Infra DX Crew</strong>.<br>It’ll contain technical musings and probably a few memes.</p>
<h4 id="TLDR"><a href="#TLDR" class="headerlink" title="TLDR"></a>TLDR</h4><ul>
<li>We (Infra DX Crew) Blog to summarise what we’re doing (with value) and experiences</li>
<li>Front-end builds take HALF THE BLOODY TIME reducing the turnaround time of devs</li>
<li>We now have some awesome performance metrics to improve the user experience</li>
<li>We’re now kicking off work to reduce those gnarly performance numbers</li>
<li>Work on a PaaS MVP is underway to allow crews to deliver faster and more autonomously</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="First-post-WOW"><a href="#First-post-WOW" class="headerlink" title="First post, WOW!"></a>First post, WOW!</h2><p>This is the first post of a near infinite series. We were wondering, in the newly founded Infra DX Crew, how we could push our communication up a notch and ensure everyone can keep on top of what we’re working on and, perhaps more importantly, <em>why</em> we are working on what we are.</p>
<p>On top of the day-to-day communication in Slack we wanted to put together a summary of our sprints where we could keep a nice archive of all our progress and experiences. We wanted this to be a little more engaging and put a personal twist on it so thought a <strong>blog</strong> would be the perfect medium for that! Writing up our experiences on a semi-regular basis should also help us consolidate our direction better.</p>
<p>So I quickly (with a lot of face palming) threw together a blog using <a href="https://hexo.io" target="_blank" rel="external">hexo</a>, created a new Lystable theme and here we are…</p>
<p><br></p>
<center><strong>The Infra DX Blog!</strong></center>

<p><img src="http://static.tumblr.com/f40cff9477fc5392797426019909d533/wihposx/uUUmspw88/tumblr_static_20130822184519uid2425.jpg" alt="wow"></p>
<p><center>wow wow wow wow wow</center><br><br></p>
<p>This sprint series (1-to-Infinity) will be central to the blog but we’ll throw a few more interesting posts in where they may be needed.</p>
<p>Let’s go!</p>
<h2 id="So-what-on-earth-is-Infra-DX"><a href="#So-what-on-earth-is-Infra-DX" class="headerlink" title="So, what on earth is Infra DX?"></a>So, what on earth is <em>Infra DX</em>?</h2><p>I’ll try to explain this quickly but I’m sure there will be a fuller post coming soon to go into more detail!</p>
<p><strong>Infra = Infrastructure</strong><br><strong>DX = Developer Experience</strong></p>
<p>On one hand we have identified a need to deliver stable and efficient infrastructure to our teams within Lystable. This could be anything from providing an easy-to-use framework for building certain parts of UI to delivering a platform which allows teams to quickly release new features <em>on their own</em>.</p>
<p>On the other “Developer Experience” encompasses everything to do with the happiness and efficiently of developers on a day-to-day basis. Ie. Making sure engineer workflows are smooth or that designers and engineers can work together without a fuss.</p>
<p>So as a crew it is our responsibility to push the quality of these experiences and tools. We aren’t the only ones though! All crews actively contribute towards these goals - we’re just a bit of dedicated focus.</p>
<h2 id="What-we-worked-on"><a href="#What-we-worked-on" class="headerlink" title="What we worked on"></a>What we worked on</h2><p>Where has our focus been?</p>
<h4 id="Tracking-apis-and-performance-metrics"><a href="#Tracking-apis-and-performance-metrics" class="headerlink" title="Tracking apis and performance metrics"></a>Tracking apis and performance metrics</h4><p>One of our big focuses as an engineering team in Q2 is on performance around our critical flows. Before you can improve performance however you need to be able to track it. This was essentially our <em>first big project</em> together on the Infra DX Crew and I’m quite pleased with the result!</p>
<p>On the one end we have a shiny new <a href="https://github.com/lystable/tracking" target="_blank" rel="external">generic tracking service</a> with the awesome <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/kibana-5-0-0-released" target="_blank" rel="external">kibana 5</a> front-end for building dashboards. On the front-end we now have some <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1787" target="_blank" rel="external">benchmarking utilities</a> and a basic <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1806" target="_blank" rel="external">tracking api</a> which acts as an interface to the back-end.</p>
<p><img src="./fe-perf.png" alt="front-end performance dashboard"></p>
<p>Above you can see one of our new dashboards for monitoring front-end performance. With these we will be able to get solid key metrics to track with the result being to deliver a faster and more responsive experience to our users!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s now super easy to start tracking your own metrics (of <em>any</em> kind) and build a dashboard. If you want help setting something up give the crew channel a shout on slack!</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="Monitoring-portal"><a href="#Monitoring-portal" class="headerlink" title="Monitoring portal"></a>Monitoring portal</h4><p>With all these new monitoring and tracking services it was beginning to be a bit of a pain to try and remember how to find anything. You’re probably even thinking <em>“where are those shiny performance dashboards you just teased us with?!”</em>.</p>
<p>Well, we decided to throw together a quick monitoring portal so now there’s just one thing to remember! You can find that at <a href="monitoring.lystable.com">monitoring.lystable.com</a></p>
<p><img src="./monitoring-portal.png" alt="monitoring portal"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>This actually sparked a bit more of an idea in my mind that we could have a portal for <em>all</em> things. Anyway, another time…</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="Massive-CI-feedback-improvements"><a href="#Massive-CI-feedback-improvements" class="headerlink" title="Massive CI feedback improvements"></a>Massive CI feedback improvements</h4><p><em>We hit under 30mins on our full front-end builds!!</em> Is that seriously a 50% improvement?! Releases are also fully done within 10mins! This is the quickest our CI has been since summer last year! I am never going to stop over-using exclaimation marks!!</p>
<p><br><br><img src="./under-30mins.png" alt="under 30min builds"></p>
<p><center>Beautiful.</center><br><br></p>
<p>An amazing effort by Yannis on this work. By parallelising our test runs, removing some build redundnacy and mastering Tetris we were able to practically halve our wild build times.</p>
<p>This isn’t all. We improved the feedback loop by notifying sooner than Circle on individual step failures. It’s common for circle to continue running after a test failure so you don’t get any notification until <em>some time later</em>. Now we let you know in slack <em>as soon</em> as something goes wrong! SWEET.</p>
<p><br><br><img src="./quick-notifications.png" alt="notifications"></p>
<p><center>Always good news first.</center><br><br></p>
<p>You can take a look at the work <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1830" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a> and <a href="https://github.com/lystable/lystable-frontend/pull/1779" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We definitely won’t be stopping here forever. When we pick this up in the future the new aim will be for under 15 minutes!</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="DX-Survey"><a href="#DX-Survey" class="headerlink" title="DX Survey"></a>DX Survey</h4><p>Nearly everybody completed the DX @ Lystable survey and the anonymised and shuffled responses are <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1rW13o5kpwmCa33OLiFCregqEzMEFgtI7lbD0wAgnics/edit#gid=0" target="_blank" rel="external">freely available</a>. In coming weeks we’ll be drilling down further into some of these topics as a DX focus.</p>
<p>Thanks again to all those who added their thoughtful responses - some really great insights!</p>
<h4 id="Crew-support"><a href="#Crew-support" class="headerlink" title="Crew support"></a>Crew support</h4><p>To help keep other crews ticking we’ve been picking up a few small product improvements or bug fixes here and there to catch some slack. So far so good and it hasn’t really affected our sprints too much!</p>
<h2 id="Some-musings"><a href="#Some-musings" class="headerlink" title="Some musings"></a>Some musings</h2><p>A few bits we’ve been thinking about.</p>
<h4 id="Driving-pull-requests-within-crews"><a href="#Driving-pull-requests-within-crews" class="headerlink" title="Driving pull requests within crews"></a>Driving pull requests within crews</h4><p>One of the things which has been growing as an issue is turnaround time on codereviews. There are many many angles to this but one of them is not really having the <em>right</em> people find the time to focus on them.</p>
<p>What we’ve seen as the beginning of a trend seems to be working really well to solving this problem. That is <strong>identify fellow crew members</strong> to help push work through. This will never be an exclusive thing, especially while we need some more people in the crews and have “cohort work”, but a crew should be able to rally together to get work shipped and a big part of that is having the work reviewed! Another great positive of this is that crew members will have the most context on the actual product requirements.</p>
<p>So a) next time you are planning your work, take into account what the crew is planning to ship in a sprint so you can make some time for reviews and b) try nudging your crew before looking beyond. It’s likely you’ll see a better response that way!</p>
<h2 id="What’s-up-next"><a href="#What’s-up-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s up next?"></a>What’s up next?</h2><p>What’s the plan, batman?</p>
<h4 id="PaaS-Platform-as-a-service"><a href="#PaaS-Platform-as-a-service" class="headerlink" title="PaaS: Platform as a service!"></a>PaaS: Platform as a service!</h4><p><img src="https://mesosphere.com/wp-content/themes/mesosphere/library/images/views/why-mesos/mesos-logo.png?v1" alt="mesos"></p>
<p>Boom! As part of a drive to enable truly autonymous crews who can ship all the time we are looking to deliver a PaaS. This should allow teams to easily create and orchestrate releases of new work with a focus being on the back-end services initially.</p>
<p>In this sprint we are planning to get a PaaS running with the nameko deployment principally flowing through that. After that (next sprint) we’ll be looking at tying in nicities such as alerting and logging to this platform. Very much MVP for now!</p>
<p>Check out <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-31" target="_blank" rel="external">INFRA-31</a> to track the work (there’s an awesome MVP checklist there).</p>
<h4 id="Improved-front-end-user-delivery"><a href="#Improved-front-end-user-delivery" class="headerlink" title="Improved front-end user delivery"></a>Improved front-end user delivery</h4><p>On the front-end to reduce the initial time it takes for users to download and start using the application we will be looking at optimising our delivered bundles.</p>
<p><br><br><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C7JTmf1W4AEJSfI.jpg:large" alt=""></p>
<p><center>Our current bundle looks something like this ^</center><br><br></p>
<p>The work here will have two focuses:</p>
<p>1) Reduce parse and initialisation time from a MASSIVE amount of javascript<br>2) Reduce download overhead of a MASSIVE amount of javascript</p>
<p>There’s a few pieces of work to move towards this but the main gist of it is a) only deliver what the user needs for their current view (code splitting) and b) just optimise the hell out of and reduce redundnacy of all the code we ship down the wire.</p>
<p>Check out <a href="https://lystable.atlassian.net/browse/INFRA-18" target="_blank" rel="external">INFRA-18</a> to track the work.</p>
<h2 id="Cya"><a href="#Cya" class="headerlink" title="Cya!"></a>Cya!</h2><p>Okay time for me to wrap up this post. I’ll leave you with Yannis’ overight airport sleeping dilemma.</p>
<p><img src="./yannis-airport.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><center><i>“Just not sure if its gonna work with my height”</i></center><br><br></p>
<blockquote>
<p>This first post was probably a bit more lengthy than future posts. There’s also a distinct lack of memes.</p>
<p>Hope you found it useful still!<br>Chris</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sprintly summary of upcoming, delivered and in-progress work for the &lt;strong&gt;Infra DX Crew&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;It’ll cont
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
